Privacy Policy
--------------

Last updated: May 10, 2019

Smashrun is committed to the privacy and protection of your data. If you ever have any concerns about security, you can always reach us via email at [hi@smashrun.com](mailto:hi@smashrun.com).

This Privacy Policy provides you with information on what data Smashrun collects, how it is used, and what choices you have with respect to that data.

“Personal Data” is information that relates to an identified or identifiable natural person. WE DO NOT AND WILL NOT SELL OR RENT YOUR PERSONAL DATA TO ANYONE, FOR ANY REASON, AT ANY TIME.

This policy covers Smashrun's treatment of your Personal Data while you are on Smashrun's website and when you use Smashrun services. This policy does not apply to the practices of third parties that Smashrun does not own or control.

### Categories of Personal Data Processed by Smashrun

**Personal data that is processed when you create a Smashrun account:**

When you create a Smashrun account, we ask you to provide your name, email address, and a display name.

Smashrun only uses your personal data as follows:

* To analyze website usage and improve our services;
* To email you any relevant announcements or notices relevant to your use of Smashrun;
* For internal research, development planning, troubleshooting problems, detecting and protecting against error, fraud, and other criminal activity;
* To enforce the Smashrun [Terms of Service](http://smashrun.com/tos); and
* As otherwise set forth in this Policy.

In addition, the display name you provide is associated with your account profile and is displayed to your Friends and Followers when you engage within Social, when you like other users’ activity, when you send a friend or follow request, when you invite someone to Smashrun, and when you submit comments.

If you provide your opt-in consent to receive email concerning new feature releases, notifications when people follow you, send you a friend request, or when someone registers from your invite, or important announcements, such as site notices and promotions, you may withdraw your consent at any time within your [Profile](https://secure.smashrun.com/settings-profile) by changing your Email Notification Preferences under Email Settings or through the unsubscribe link at the bottom of our emails.

We use your registration data to help improve Smashrun, to keep you notified of important announcements, and to create a better experience when using our site.

**Additional personal data that is processed if you choose to provide it:**

You can add supplemental information to your profile such as your birthday, gender, height, weight, and resting heart rate.

We use this information to perform the following calculations:

* Your birthday and gender to estimate your max heart rate, and for demographic ranks;
* Your height and weight to calculate Net Calories Burned; and
* Your resting heart rate to calculate your Heart Rate Reserve and Heart Rate Zones.

You can withdraw your consent at any time by deleting or disabling this information from your [Profile](https://secure.smashrun.com/settings-profile) under User Information.

You can optionally provide additional information to your profile, which helps us calculate certain metrics that are useful to you for analyzing your run data.

**Personal data that is processed when you sign in via Facebook:**

You may choose to create a Smashrun account or sign in using your Facebook credentials. If you choose to do this, the first time you do so, you will be asked whether you agree that Facebook may provide certain information to Smashrun, such as your name, email address, profile photo, and gender.

If you decide that you would like to search for your Facebook friends on Smashrun, Facebook will ask you if you agree to providing us with your list of friends. Smashrun _does not store your list of Facebook friends_. We only use it to help you find your Facebook friends on Smashrun.

The only information that Smashrun retains and processes is your name, email address, profile photo, and gender. If you do not want any of this information to be shared with Smashrun, then you can simply create an account with your name and email address or sign in with your Smashrun credentials instead of your Facebook credentials.

Signing in via Facebook provides us with information that you can edit or delete on Smashrun. If you choose to do so, you can also search for your Facebook friends on Smashrun. You can disconnect your Facebook account at any time.

**Personal data that is processed when you upload running activities to Smashrun:**

Your Smashrun profile, by design, is only useful when you upload running activities. This includes activity data such as distance, pace, duration, heart rate, and, when provided by the data source, location, cadence, power, and elevation.

When you upload or sync your runs to Smashrun, you control whether others can see your stats by managing the Privacy Settings in your Smashrun account.

Smashrun processes your activity data, if you choose to upload it to Smashrun, to enable you to analyze your running stats and track your running goals, and, if you wish, share your activity data with others as permitted by your Privacy Settings.

You are always in control of the privacy of your running data. To hide specific information regarding your runs, hide your stats from everyone, or to tell Google not to index your page, visit your Privacy Settings within your [Profile](https://secure.smashrun.com/settings-profile).

**Personal data that is processed when you connect your Smashrun account to an integrated 3rd party application:**

If you choose to connect your Smashrun account to integrated mobile apps such as iSmoothrun, Run.GPS, Sportractive, or Caledos Runner, or web applications such as Garmin Connect, TomTom MySports, or Microsoft Health, we will obtain your running activities and associated activity data from such account(s).

You can withdraw your consent at any time by revoking access to your Smashrun account within your [Profile](https://secure.smashrun.com/settings-profile) under Connected Apps and/or within your [Synced Devices](https://secure.smashrun.com/settings-sync).

We import running activities from 3rd party applications that you authorize to connect to your Smashrun account. You can revoke access at any time.

**Personal data that is processed when you communicate with Smashrun:**

When you interact with Smashrun to receive support via email, our Facebook page, or our Twitter account, we collect personal data, such as your name and email address, and information about your Smashrun account. We may also create event logs that are useful in diagnosing errors you may have found in site functionality or site performance-related issues. We only use this information to provide you customer and product support.

We use your preferred method of contact when helping you resolve an issue. We also create logs that we use to diagnose errors so that we can fix them.

### Categories of Recipients of Personal Data

**Other Smashrun users**

Smashrun believes that social accountability can be inherently motivating and can help runners maintain an active lifestyle. For this reason, your Smashrun dashboard may be seen by others depending on your privacy settings; you can always update your privacy within your [Profile](https://secure.smashrun.com/settings-profile) under Privacy Settings.

If you consent to using Social, you can join Groups and Challenges, and interact with its members, your Friends, and your Followers. By using Social, you will be displaying your recent running activity to other Smashrun users.

A public profile does not make you discoverable. It just makes it easier for you to share your runs with people you know. To interact with other Smashrunners, you'll have to provide your consent.

**Integrated 3rd party applications or web platforms utilizing the Smashrun API**

If you choose to authorize Smashrun to permit a 3rd party, such as an integrated mobile app or web platform, to access your activity data in your Smashrun account, then we will share such data with the 3rd party.

We will not share your activity data on Smashrun without your explicit consent. Once you direct us to share data with a 3rd party, the 3rd party’s handling of your personal data is the responsibility of that 3rd party and you should carefully review the 3rd party’s privacy policy.

You can choose to stop sharing data with the 3rd party app or web platform at any time within your [Profile](https://secure.smashrun.com/settings-profile) under Connected Apps.

We only share your running activity data with apps you authorize to have access to your Smashrun data.

**Other Disclosures**

We may disclose personal data about you to others:

* if we have your valid consent to do so;
* to enforce any of our terms and conditions or policies;
* when required by any applicable law, rule, regulation, subpoena or other legal process;
* as necessary to pursue available legal remedies or defend legal claims; or
* in connection with sale of our company or any of its assets, or disposition of its assets in bankruptcy.

We may release your information to authorities where required by law.

### Transfers of Personal Data

When you create a Smashrun account, add personal data in your profile, or upload data to your Smashrun account, your personal data will be collected and stored on servers in the United States. Our hosting provider is an SSAE-SOC 1 Type 2, SSAE-SOC 2 Type 2, HIPAA, PCI and ISAE-3402 compliant company, is an active participant in the EU-U.S. Privacy Shield Framework and Swiss-U.S. Privacy Shield Framework, pursuant to [Art. 44, Rec. 102](https://gdpr-info.eu/recitals/no-102/) of the E.U. GDPR.

Any data you enter in your profile or upload to your Smashrun account goes to our servers, located in a secured data center in the United States.

### Cookies and Similar Technology

**Website**

Smashrun uses standard web browser cookies. Smashrun uses cookies in the following ways:

* to maintain your logged-in state to the website;
* to help us determine whether you read the blog posts that we write;
* to help us determine your timezone to update demographic ranks; and
* to store your language preference.

It is highly likely that other future site functionality may utilize cookies as well. Rest assured, however, no personally identifiable information is ever stored inside these cookies, and they can be safely deleted at any time.

We will track you via industry-standard web browser cookies, so we can remember you and help load things a bit faster for your next visit.

**Analytics and Conversion Tracking**

Smashrun uses Google Analytics to help us evaluate how users and visitors interact with the site.

Google Analytics uses cookies to collect standard Internet log information and visitor behavior information in an anonymous form. The information generated by the cookie about your use of the website, including your IP address, is transmitted to Google. This information is then used to analyze how users and visitors interact with the site and to compile reports on site activity. Google will not associate your IP address with any other data held by Google.

You may refuse the use of cookies by selecting the appropriate settings on your browser. However, please note that if you do this, you may not be able to use the full functionality of this website. For more information or to opt-out, please see [Google’s Advertising and Privacy Policy](https://policies.google.com/technologies/ads).

Additionally, Smashrun has implemented Twitter website tags to monitor site visits via Twitter and to help us track the actions taken by a visitor after viewing or engaging with a tweet from Smashrun. This information will also be used to help us measure the results of our marketing efforts through promoted tweets. To opt-out, please see [Twitter’s privacy controls for tailored ads](https://help.twitter.com/en/safety-and-security/privacy-controls-for-tailored-ads).

By using Smashrun, you consent to the processing of data about your interaction with this site by Google Analytics and Twitter in the manner and for the purposes set out above.

We use Google Analytics to understand how our users interact with Smashrun and use Twitter website tags to track site visits via Twitter.

### Retention of Personal Data

We will retain your personal data as long as your account on Smashrun is active. You can always request a bulk export of all your Smashrun data and deactivate your account within your [Account](https://secure.smashrun.com/settings-account) page.

Once your account is deactivated, _all of your data will be purged from our database within 24 hours_, and we will notify any connected integrated 3rd party applications or web platforms of your account deactivation.

You can exercise your right to delete all personal data on Smashrun at any time by deactivating your account.

### Privacy Policy Updates

The Smashrun Privacy Policy is subject to change at any time, and we will notify all of our users of any amendments made to our Policy. The Policy's most recently revised date will always appear at the top of the Policy. Changes take effect immediately upon posting.

For any questions, comments, concerns, or feedback regarding this Policy or any other privacy or security concerns, please contact us via email at [support@smashrun.com](mailto:support@smashrun.com) or [hi@smashrun.com](mailto:hi@smashrun.com).

This Privacy Policy may change. We will notify you when this happens.

-------------------------------------------------------

### The science behind your running

Smashrun was built by [chris](https://chrislukic.com/), [steve](http://www.ikickass.com/shortthoughts), and [jacklyn](https://jacklyngiron.com/)

Català English (U.S.) English (UK) Français Español (Spain) Nederlands Русский Español (LatAm) 中文（正體） Norsk Bokmål Slovencina Dansk Deutsch Italiano Português Magyar العَرَبِيةُ Ceština Português (Brasil) Svenska Eλληνικά हिन्दी Bahasa Indonesia Norsk Nynorsk Српска Afrikaans 日本語 Polski

### Questions, problems, ideas or just want to help? [hi@smashrun.com](mailto:hi@smashrun.com)
